# **Julius Chan**

juliuschanjq@gmail.com ❖

**❖** Singaporean

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/julius-chan

Website: juliuschanjq.github.io

Highly driven individual with a proven track record of excelling in diverse environments. With an academic foundation in STEM and valuable industry experience, I possess the resilience that is needed to effectively resolve complex issues. My approach is guided with logical thinking as I consistently strive to find solutions to problems in fast-paced settings.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Open Government Products, Govtech Singapore Sep 2022 – Mar 2024

## **Product Operations Executive**

- Coordinated with government agencies to successfully launched over 400 websites on product platform resulting in cost savings of million dollars within project deadlines.
- Collaborated seamlessly with cross-functional teams, including Software Engineers, Product Designers, and Product Managers, to actively gather and implement user feedback for optimizing feature discoverability.
- Provided comprehensive support at both tier 1 and tier 2 levels, effectively resolving a diverse range of problems and inquiries from stakeholders.
- Migrated website content into product system using CMS technology with HTML, Markdown & CSS.
- Took charge of onboarding and managing a team of executives during the migration project.

### NexusGuard

#### Jan 2021 - Jun 2022

## Apprenticeship, Cybersecurity Specialist

- Acquired valuable front-line experiences and honed problem-solving skills through collaboration with assigned SMEs
  in the industry.
- Led activities and conducted case studies encompassing system and network management, vulnerability assessment, data analysis, risk assessments, policy analysis, and the strategic design of a sales-oriented business strategy.
- Attained certifications in Web Application Security and Certified Cybersecurity Specialist.

## DBS Bank via PersolKelly Oct 2020 – Oct 2021

### **Customer Service Officer**

- Effectively communicated. comprehended, and proactively addressed customer inquiries.
- Successfully directed customers to mobile banking adoption and taught them about the benefits of digital migration.
- Handled and supported diverse customers needs with cash management, account opening, and card queries.
- Played a pivotal role in contributing to Branch's KPI through referral of customers for cross-selling of investment products.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Coventry University**

2023 - 2024

Bachelor of Science (Upper Second-Class Honors), Computer Science

## Nanyang Technological University

2021 - 2022

Professional Certificate, Cybersecurity Specialist

# Temasek Polytechnic

2020 - 2023

Diploma (GPA:3.53), Applied Artificial Intelligence

#### **CERTIFICATIONS, SKILLS & INTERESTS**

- Certifications: Certified Cybersecurity Specialist (NexusGuard), Professional Certificate in Product Management (Aha!), Knowledge Certificate in Web 3.0 (National University of Singapore), Post Diploma in Business Intelligence (Temasek Polytechnic 2023)
- Skills: Communication, Adaptability, Self-Awareness, Web Development, Python, Cloud Technologies, Data Analytics, AI/ML
- Interests: Weightlifting, Photography, Vinyl Collection, Video Games, Future Trends